rhino3d.com 2019-12-31

# McNeel North America - Privacy Policy

_NOTE: Unless you are a Customer or User, providing any information to us is_ **_optional_** _. We will still do our best to help; it is just much easier if we know what is important to you and have a way to contact you._

## 1\. Definitions

Throughout this document, we may use certain words or phrases, and it is important that you understand the meaning of them. The following is a non-exhaustive list of definitions of words and phrases found in this document:

  * "Program" refers to our software application.
  * "Programs" refers to our software applications, including "Rhinoceros," "iRhino 3D," "Flamingo," "Brazil," and "Bongo".
  * "Installer" refers to the program that installs our Program.
  * "McNeel" refers to our company, known as "Robert McNeel & Associates", our Site, our Products our Service, or a combination of all or some of the preceding definitions, depending on the context in which the word is used.
  * "Service" refers to the services that we provide, including our Site, our Programs, our Installer.
  * "Site" refers to our websites, including: http://www.mcneel.com, https://www.rhino3d.com, http://discourse.mcneel.com.
  * "User" refers to anyone who uses our Program, Installer, Site, or Service in general.
  * "You" refers to you, the person who is governed by this Privacy Policy.

## 2\. Information we collect

### Identifying Information

When you download we collect certain personal information from you that can be used to identify you, including any information that we deem necessary to provide you with our Service or which you may provide to us voluntarily. The information we collect from you, to the extent that it is private, is disclosed only in accordance with our Terms of Service and/or this Privacy Policy.

### Non-identifying information

Whenever you visit our Site, we may collect non-identifying information from you, such as your IP address, referring URL, browser, operating system, cookie information, and Internet Service Provider. Without a subpoena, voluntary compliance on the part of your Internet Service Provider, or additional records from a third party, this information alone cannot usually be used to identify you.

### Anonymous usage statistics

Some Programs and their Installers send anonymous information to McNeel servers. This anonymous information includes a randomly generated globally unique identifier (GUID) that is stored on your computer. This allows us to differentiate between one person experiencing a problem one hundred times, and one hundred people experiencing a problem one time each. Each product and installer provides an option to opt-out of sending anonymous usage statistics. See documentation for your product for details.

## 3\. What we do with your information

  * Keep it confidential.
  * Improve this website so that it better fits your needs.
  * Improve our products so that they better fit your needs.
  * Build an electronic newsletter subscription list so that we can notify subscribers of update information on our products (and related products), support, training, and events.

## 4\. What we do NOT do with your information

  * Sell or provide your information to anyone outside this organization.
  * Provide your information to our resellers, distributors, or OEMs.

## 5\. Updating your information

To change your email address, [ **email**](mailto:bob.mcneel@mcneel.com?subject=Change%20Address&body=Please%20change%20my%20email%20address%20from:%20____________%20to:%20______________) us both your **old** and **new** email addresses. You can update your Rhino Account details [here](https://accounts.rhino3d.com/?controller=home).

## 6\. Cancel your subscription

To remove your email from our eNew subscription list, forward the last eNews you received from us to **[remove@mcneel.com](mailto:remove@mcneel.com)  
**

## 7\. Third-party websites

McNeel may post links to third-party websites on its Site or within its Programs. These third-party websites are not screened for privacy or security issues by McNeel, and you release us from any liability for the conduct of these third-party websites.

Please be aware that this Privacy Policy and any other policies in place, along with any amendments, do not create rights enforceable by third parties or require disclosure of any personal information relating to members of the Service or Site. McNeel bears no responsibility for the information collected or used by any advertiser or third-party website. Please review the privacy policy and terms of service for each site you visit through third-party links.

## 8\. Third-party access to your information

Although you are entering into an Agreement with McNeel to disclose your information to us, we do use third-party individuals or organizations to assist us, including contractors, web hosts, or others.

Throughout the course of our provision of our Service to you, we may delegate our authority to collect, access, use, and disseminate your information. For example, our web host stores the information that you provide to us, and we may hire outside contractors to perform maintenance or assist us in securing our Site.

It is therefore necessary that you grant the third parties we may use in the course of our business the same rights that you afford us under this Privacy Policy. For this reason, you hereby agree that for every authorization which you grant to us in this Privacy Policy, you also grant to any third party that we may hire, contract, or otherwise retain the services of to operate, maintain, repair, or otherwise improve or preserve our website or its underlying files or systems. You agree not to hold us liable for the actions of any of these third parties, even if we would normally be held vicariously liable for their actions and that you must take legal action against them directly should they commit any tort or other actionable wrong against you.

Without limiting the generality of the foregoing, you authorize us to collect, share, store, exchange, analyze, and otherwise use your information in conjunction with these and other service providers: 

Service | Description  
---|---  
[Google Analytics](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/) | Compiles visitor statistics on our web sites. You can opt out of Google analytics using a [browser extension](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).  
[Google Cloud Platform](https://cloud.google.com/security/privacy/) | Provides cloud servers and services, in service regions across the world, to host, deliver, and speed up web our web sites and downloads. Some of your data may be stored on these servers.  
[Amazon Web Services](https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/) | Provides cloud servers and services, in service regions across the world, to host, deliver, and speed up web our web sites and downloads. Also provides services for sending email. Some of your data may be stored on these servers.  
[Microsoft Azure](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/TrustCenter/Privacy/default.aspx) | Provides cloud servers and services, in service regions across the world, to host, deliver, and speed up web our web sites and downloads. Some of your data may be stored on these servers.  
[RayGun](https://raygun.com/privacy) | Raygun provides error, crash and performance monitoring for software teams.  
[Apple, Inc.](https://apple.com/privacy) | Our products that run on Apple devices may be distributed via Apple.  
[SparkPost](https://www.sparkpost.com/policies/privacy/) | We send email using SparkPost.  
[SupportBee](https://supportbee.com/privacy-policy) | Emails you send to our sales and support teams are processed by SupportBee.  
  
## 9\. Release of Your Information for legal purposes

At times it may become necessary to release your information in response to a request from a government agency or a private litigant. You agree that we may disclose your information to a third party where we believe, in good faith, that it is desirable to do so for a civil action, criminal investigation, or other legal matter. In the event that we receive a subpoena affecting your privacy, we may elect to notify you to give you an opportunity to file a motion to quash the subpoena, or we may attempt to quash it ourselves, but we are not obligated to do either. We may also proactively report you and release your information to third parties where we believe that it is prudent to do so for legal reasons, such as our belief that you have engaged in fraudulent activities. You release us from any damages that may arise from or relate to the release of your information to a request from law enforcement agencies or private litigants.

## 10\. Commercial and non-commercial communications

By providing information to the Site that forms the basis of communication with you, such as contact information, you waive all rights to file complaints concerning unsolicited emails from McNeel since, by providing such information, you agree to receive communications from us or anyone else covered under this Privacy Policy. However, you may unsubscribe from certain communications by notifying McNeel that you no longer wish to receive solicitations or information and we will endeavor to remove you from the database.

## 11\. Security measures

We take certain measures to enhance the security of our Site and Service, as it is in our interest to do so. However, we make no representations as to the security or privacy of your information. It is in our interest to keep our websites secure, but we recommend that you use anti-virus software, firewalls, and other precautions to protect yourself from security threats.

## 12\. Your California online privacy rights

McNeel permits residents of California to use its services. Therefore, it is the intent of McNeel to comply with the California Business and Professions Code §§ 22575-22579. If you are a California resident, you may request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to any third parties for their direct marketing purposes. Various provisions throughout this Privacy Policy address requirements of the California privacy statutes. In summary, you must presume that we collect electronic information from all visitors. You may contact us at sales@mcneel.com with any questions.

## 13\. International transfer

Your information may be transferred to and maintained on computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. If you are located outside the United States and choose to provide information to us, McNeel transfers Personal Information to the United States and processes it there. Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

## 14\. Amendments

We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time. When we amend this Privacy Policy, we will update this page accordingly. You must read this page each time you use our Service, and your continued use of our Service shall constitute your acceptance of any such amendments.
